University of Connecticut, Honors Program Records 1987.0008
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
University of Connecticut, Honors Program Records
undated, 1983-2010
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1987.0008
36.4 Linear Feet
Administrative and academic files of the honors program at the University of Connecticut. The records contain general information on students enrolled in the program, course materials, scholarship and award information, and specific information concerning students enrolled in the Pre-Med honors program.
Access
The collection is open and available for research with the exception of student files.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records are transferred to the University Archives periodically by the Honors Program.
History
The Honors program at the University of Connecticut has been educating students since its inception in 1964. The highly selective program is designed to provide the richest possible collegiate experience for intellectually-gifted and highly motivated undergraduate students. The honors program provides challenging academics, a personalized collegiate environment, a community designed for individual, social, and cultural development, and engagement and leadership beyond the classroom for the ten percent of undergraduate students who are enrolled as honors students. The program is made up of between 400 and 500 incoming students each year, and graduates approximately 300 students each year. As a part of the program students conduct undergraduate research projects in their area of study, producing an honors thesis during their senior year which the university saves in its archives. Graduates of the honors program have gone on to work for some of Connecticut's top companies, attend graduate programs at the nation's top universities, and been the recipients of the nation's most prestigious scholarships.
Scope and Content Note
The Honors Program Records are comprised of two series. The first series contains a variety of materials related to the honors program in general, and include information of honors courses, regional campus programs, program admissions, honors students, awards and scholarships, and administrative records of the program. The first series is comprised of undated materials, as well as materials from the period 1993 to 2010. The second series is related to students in the Pre-Med honors program, and contains administrative records, manuscripts, and notes on students majoring in various science programs. The second series is comprised of materials dating from 1983 to 1995. Student files are restricted.
Archives (institutions); Administrative records
- Series I: Administrative records, undated
  - Nutmeg recruitment (Box A1)
  - Nutmeg Scholar polices (Box A1)
  - Regional Campus programs (Box A1)
  - Individualized major (Box A1)
  - BGS Honors program (Box A1)
  - Course availablity (Box A1)
  - Freshman seminars (Box A1)
  - Freshman experience (Box A1)
  - Study skills workshop (Box A1)
  - Board of Associate Directors (Box A1)
  - Honors Teaching Capacity surveys, 1997 (Box A1)
  - Schedules of classes and catalog changes (Box A1)
  - Honors courses, 1998-1999 (Box A1)
  - Course evaluation project (Box A1)
  - Possible Honors courses (Box A1)
  - New courses (Box A1)
  - Department Directors breakfast (Box A1)
  - Handbook (Box A1)
  - Departmental programs (Box A1)
  - Admissions policy (Box A2)
  - Entering Class Fall, 1993 (Box A2)
  - Enerting Class Fall, 1994 (Box A2)
  - Admissions Fall, 1995 (Box A2)
  - Data (Box A2)
  - Entering Class Fall, 1996 (Box A2)
  - Entering Class Fall, 1997 (Box A2)
  - Entering Class Fall, 1998 (Box A2)
  - Student lists (Box A2)
  - Recruitment efforts, 1997-1998 (Box A2)
  - Connecticut Honors seminar (Box A2)
  - Orientation and Summer registration (Box A2)
  - Orientation, 1994 (Box A2)
  - Orientation, 1995-1996 (Box A2)
  - Orientation Summer, 1996 (Box A2)
  - Orientation sessions, 1997 (Box A2)
  - Orientation Summer, 1998 (Box A2)
  - One Day Orientation (Box A2)
  - Who's Who (Box A2)
  - Outstanding Senior Women's award (Box A2)
  - Minority recruitment (Box A2)
  - Day of Pride Students in Honors Program (Box A2)
  - Official graduation lists (Box A2)
  - Scholarships--Larry Gramling, 1996 (Box A2)
  - Pollack Scholarship (through Engineering) (Box A2)
  - Weisel Competition (Box A2)
  - Babbidge Scholar awards (Box A2)
  - Wal-Mart Scholar awards (Box A2)
  - National Scholarship competitions (Box A2)
  - Oaklawn Foundation (Box A2)
  - Hood, Polayes, Alaimo and Weber awards (Box A2)
  - Honors Program Merit scholarships (Box A2)
  - Fellowships-Merit base (Box A2)
  - Washignton Internship program student files (Box A2)
  - Presidential "Honors Floors" (Box A3)
  - Presidential complex (Box A3)
  - Service Learning possibilities (Box A3)
  - UPLD (Box A3)
  - Conversion policies (Box A3)
  - Mini-course forms (Box A3)
  - National Honors Meeting, St. Louis, 1993 (Box A3)
  - New England States' Honors programs (Box A3)
  - Honors newsletters, student (Box A3)
  - Greshman interest (Box A3)
  - Study skills workshop (Box A3)
  - National student exchange (Box A3)
  - Publicity (Box A3)
  - Open House (Box A3)
  - Unsuccessful theses (Box A3)
  - Allied Health Orientation (Box A3)
  - Fundraising (Box A3)
  - External reviews of UConn's Honors Program (Box A3)
  - Financial aid policies--other Universities (Box A3)
  - Awards for newsletter (Box A3)
  - Results of scholarship competitions (Box A3)
  - Memoranda (Box A3)
  - Alumni newsletters--Honors (Box A3)
  - Alumni newsletter--UConn (Box A3)
  - Newsletter and brochure ideas (Box A3)
  - Student achievements (Box A3)
  - Scholastic Standard committee (Box A3)
  - Alumni relations (Box A3)
  - Senate By-Laws changes (Box A3)
  - Honors societies (Box A3)
  - Long term planning (Box A3)
  - Emmert memoranda (Box A3)
  - Program summaries (Box A3)
  - Honors program in comparative perspective (Box A3)
  - Data (Box A3)
  - Piece of Mind (Box A3)
  - Students' concerns (Box A3)
  - Probation, Dismissals, Warnings (Box A3)
  - HPCC (Box A3)
  - Student evaluations and HPCC (Box A3)
  - Honors logo project (Box A3)
  - UConn Honors brochure (Box A3)
  - Newsletters, 1993- (Box A3)
  - Research Opportunities for Honors students (Box A3)
  - Frontiers of undergraduate education (Box A3)
  - Honors house supervisor (Box A3)
  - Honors house repair (Box A3)
  - Honors house activities (Box A3)
  - Undergraduate research committee (Box A3)